# Gareth Gomersall

## Web Developer

After several years working in the financial markets as a Money Broker I started my own online company. This is when I fell in love with coding. In 2015 I successfully completed the General Assembly WDI bootcamp, furthering my knowledge of web design and coding.

me@garethg.com
mo c garoting.com

in linkedin.com/in/ggomersall

twitter.com/GarethG\_

github.com/ggomersall

garethg.com

07585314836

## **Experience:**

#### Junior Developer, MedicAnimal - Jan 27 2016 to current

This is my first commercial role as a Junior Front-End Developer. The role focuses on implementing new features for the website and fixing existing bugs with in an agile working environment, running on a two week sprint schedule. This role requires me to work collaboratively with the business and marketing department. Languages used are HTML, LESS/SASS and Javascript, as well as working closely with the Back-End Developers developing in Java.

#### Part-time Instructor, General Assembly London - April 2016 to current

Part-time instructor for Getting started in Web Development at General Assembly, introducing non developers to the world of coding and web development.

#### GA WDI, London - Sept 28 2015 to Dec 18 2015

WDI is a three month bootcamp focusing on teaching their students numerous web technologies while preparing students to become Junior Web Developers working within an agile environment. The technologies that I learnt were: HTML/HAML, CSS/SASS, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Node.js, jQuery, JavaScript, AngularJS, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, TDD, Heroku, AWS, Git and working with third party API's.

#### **Projects:**

#### **Devign Hunt**

My final project was to build a meet-up style website for freelance designers and developers to meet up and collaborate on projects together.

The project was built on a Mean stack using AngularJS, Node.js, Express and MongoDB.

<u>github.com/ggomersall/devign-frontend</u> <u>github.com/ggomersall/devign-api</u> <u>devignhunt.herokuapp.com</u>

#### **DeskBrews**

My second project was a B2C website allowing companies or individual to order craft beers for deliveries on fridays.

The project was built using Ruby on Rails and implementing the Stripe API for payments.

https://github.com/ggomersall/WDI-PROJECT-2 www.deskbrews.com

#### Plannerr

This was a group project. We built a mobile first app that allowed users to create an event and invite their friends, allowing each friend to suggest a different activity by utilising the Google Maps API.

The project was built using Node.js, Express, jQuery and MongoDB.

github.com/FinnCavanagh/plannerr-api github.com/FinnCavanagh/Plannerr-Client finncavanagh.github.io/Plannerr-Client/

#### **Duck Hunt**

My first project was based on the original 80's game Duck Hunt, but combining a two player game.

The project was built using HTML5, CSS and JavaScript.

https://github.com/ggomersall/WDI-PROJECT-1 https://calm-sea-7889.herokuapp.com/

## **Experience Continued:**

#### Money Broker - ICAP PLC - Nov 2007 to May 2012

I started working on the EURO FX desk as a Junior Money Broker supporting the Senior Brokers with voice and electronic deals, deal ticket entry, trading deals with external brokers and other worldwide ICAP trading desks.

My role evolved to moving to the Emerging Market desk, trading in Hungarian and Romanian FX.

In 2011 I moved to ICAP Bahrain to trade in Middle Eastern FX currencies and SPOT, dealing with clients from Saudi Arabia, Bahrain, Kuwait, Dubai and Qatar.

#### Desktop Support - ICAP PLC - April 2006 to Nov 2007

The role at ICAP as Desktop Support was to support all front office brokers and back office support staff in their day to day IT issues. The support covered Microsoft products, various Money Broking tools and software and printers and hardware issues.

I was the Lead Engineer on maintaining and supporting the users mobile devices i.e. rollouts, troubleshooting, technical issues and liaising with third party vendors.

During my post I was elected as the Lead Support Engineer to our Copenhagen office.

#### Skills:

CSS	Node.js		Postgres	•••00
HTML	JavaScript	•••00	MongoDB	•••00
Ruby on Rails	JQuery	•••00	AngularJS	•••00

## **Education:**

High school - St Albans College, South Africa, 1998

Web Development Immersive - General Assembly, London, Sept 2015 - Dec 2015

## More About Me:

After moving to the UK in 1998 i've been bitten by the travel bug, I enjoy exploring new countries and experiencing new cultures.

As well as this I'm considered a bit of a geek by my friends and loved ones as I get far too excited about all things tech, and enjoy learning new languages.

## Things I Love:

